But I'm going to keep going because we don't
have much time, so we have
45 minutes. Hang in there. You'll learn the
deep secret of the masters. And there's
how to sleep in class with your eyes
open.
Okay,
the people who didn't finish the
Disney training would still be like that, they'd be like that, but
the real masters would open up. So they
do the daisies of the super
advanced ones. They tell them like this
every five minutes, so they
definitely look
awake.
This will be... this is a skill of the
high master. You can participate in it, you
can practice it today or tomorrow.
I'm going to go through your homework. You're
here somewhere. I'd like to
teach this class
the traditional way. Okay, I don't want to just
go through the homework. So one
class, we're going to do it the old-fashioned way,
just for fun. And this class... and I
said it would be fun to teach this class
the real way. If I'm going to
do it the real way, it's also going to
probably take up the
rest of today and tomorrow. So we're
behind schedule. We usually are. And I already
told you I wasn't going to be behind
now, but I did.
Okay, here we go. I'm going to teach the
old-fashioned way. Okay, are you...  Okay, this is a
very famous part of him,
the three main paths.
Who yelled at me, "Why don't you fix my
own mistake on the homework?" But I said, "Sorry,
but everyone's going to have to
do it with their pencil." Where do I care? This
is one of the most important lines of
how the three main paths begin,
and I'd like to go with you
in the traditional way. I'm going to teach you
the most difficult part of the
Buddha's teachings. The first line: I'm going to
teach you the most difficult of all the
Buddha's teachings. I'm going to teach you the
path that all the Bodhisattvas think is
so good and so cool. That's a
second line. The third line: I'm going to
help you enter.
What it means is a special word.
For a part, for 100 dollars
and MGM, I'm going. It
means that in Tibet, there are many rivers
because there's snow everywhere. If there are no
bridges because they don't have cement or anything like that,
then you have to
find the lowest part to cross
with the horse. So it means
the easiest place to enter a
stream, the easiest part to cross.
So they are layers. His own
book calls them "The Book." This is the world for
the people who see you.  People who have
very good karma and who are Tanda,
who want to achieve enlightenment—
because I'm emphasizing that
because that's Gay's real name—he is, so
if you want to
impress him, you can tell him, and we
studied him the other night, and he's going to
say, "That's my name."
Really,
his name is Love Saint Andreu, it
's liberation.
Where did he get his name,
Lobsang? From Greenwich, it's his first
name.
He inherited it, a monk made him a monk.
Then the last line quotes
Mitch, and from here it goes, by the way,
many people come to me and say, "
I would like to learn Tibetan," and it's a very
good idea. So listen,
and we have three teams trying to
find the original Sanskrit texts
that were destroyed in India.
So maybe we can find 100.
There are three teams that have been
working for 12 years; we've been
paying them for 12 years. Big teams that
have only digitized about 100 pages,
less than 100 pages. It's very difficult
to find the holy books in
Sanskrit,
in the Tibetan language, including the
originals from India. There are 300.  A thousand books,
each one incredible,
without bragging, it's one hundred percent
incredible books by far the
greatest spiritual literature in the
world. People just don't know about it. John
Brady is working to stop that,
very well. And why am I bragging about
it? I don't remember
anyway. So, people
worry me, the question is, what do you
teach them in Tibetan? So, memorize
this poem. It's 14 verses,
it takes about two minutes to recite, and
normally the books we memorize
take an hour and a half or two to recite.
You can recite this in, I don't know, like
three minutes.
So, if you're interested in learning
Tibetan, learn the prayers
first, Sushi, and learn those first,
and then go to this book. This
is very easy, 14 verses. And Nick
asked me how I could start my Tibetan,
and I said, memorize it, and he did, and his
Tibetan is very good. Now, it plants
a very good seed in your mind. By the
way, I think it won't even come to the
translation course anymore. Everyone can come to the
translation course. You don't have to be a
translator.
We have secondary translators who will
translate from English to Spanish, Russian to
Mandarin. They can always come to the school;
it's very...  It's difficult, five hours a day, six
hours a day, very, very heavy, but your
mind is going to grow really big,
then you can teach like Stanley,
I'm not kidding, he has all this stuff
that's going to grow in his head as
everything got bigger,
I'm giving him a lot of pride so I can
break it later. So the last
verse of the last line is, I'll do my
best to explain that SS,
the essence of all
Buddhist teachings, and number 2, the path that
all Bodhisattvas think is
very sexy, number 3, the entry point
for those who want to go to
freedom. I'm going to explain it as best I
can, so Song Pak Kapa says, as
best I can, I'm just a fool, and
that's a tradition, a traditional way
of starting a scripture. Say that the
pan, yum yum yum, that Michael says, to
have an altar, to have a throne, teaches to
inhabit more the mental functions of whatever.
Traditionally, the first thing he
does is, traditionally for 2000
years, you appear on the stage and you say
on the throne and you say
all these negative emotions more than
anyone in this room, and  Thank you for
letting me teach, and Michael says to
you today, thank you for letting me teach you. I
know you're all mute. I
know I'm the only non-Buddha in the room,
and I hope it's a lot of fun teaching you,
so thank you for that, and I'm going to do
the best I can.
So you're capable. He's doing what they
call humble, okay, but it's true, it's really
true, and never
forget that you're going to be teachers of
Asia. It's very possible that every
student you meet, whether they're Buddhist or not, is
just trying to get you to
talk about it. Michael talks about
jealousy ten thousand times in 40 years.
Maybe you'll understand. Do
n't be so mute and tell them, "I
'm not a Buddha, Gisela."
Maybe this other guy is. Very well,
thank you for letting me teach. That's
traditional, by the way. What's the other
thing that's happening in that line?
Traditionally, he's promising
to finish, that he's going to finish free, and
this is a comment on the
Buddha's commitments, and it's traditionally one of
the two strongest Buddhist commitments: I promise I'm
going to finish
this class. I promise I'm going to do these
positions.  of yoga over and over again before unless I
die before the class,
okay, this is a commitment, it's a
commitment of a Buddhist teacher.
So you go there with your own
students this year and you base yourself on
teaching Course 1, and in your mind you have to
say, I'm not going to finish unless I
die. And that's very interesting. In the
scriptures, there are books that end in
the middle of a sentence
because because the guy who
was doing the manuscript died.
[Music]
And it's considered one of the most
serious promises you can make. How do you get on with
finishing your book? You're going to
die trying. And it's always said
in the first verse, "I'm going to do it,
complete this. I promise I'm going to die
before this law." It's going to have to be
like 25 years old. Very good luck.
[Music] So now
here's
[Music]
the big date,
the biggest thing about this book. The
coolest thing about the first verse of the three
main paths is that about
everyone wanting to guess what he did
and put the three main paths in
the first verse, he hid them in the
first verse. We've already covered them.  The
first three paths, the three
main centers, so I give you permission
to memorize the three
main paths. Just by memorizing the first
verse, you can play pranks on people you
want. You want them to recite the three
main paths, just the first
verse, but they'll say there are only 13 other
verses. And tell them, no, it's all in the first
verse. Pavón almost said it, and it's true.
Let's experience it. Are you ready? And I'm going to
change the English
as much as I can,
and the Tibetan syntax and the
English syntax are reversed,
so you have to translate the last
line first. I promise I'm going to write, I'm
going to finish this book, which is the
essence of all the high teachings
of Buddhism. Which of the three
main ones is that
renunciation? Yesterday you asked me, Anís Rama
in Sanskrit, knicks
definitely means like, nor tarts, and it will be
nothing. It's like
pra sarita, like dressing your
legs, for sarita, which for tarazona,
then for cerrito means to
scatter. The word samsara comes from
the same root, to separate, like to scatter.
The word book search generates, and it's serious to
write, it comes from there,
and  That's why "right" is spelled with "but oh
well, you don't care then." The essence
of all the many teachings of the
victorious is renunciation. I'm tired, I'm tired, I'm tired. There's so
much
pain in this world.
Yoga teachers give pain to their
students. Just kidding.
I like to fly. Not from Andrés Gas.
The path that all the saints, the
holy children, recommend. I translated this a long time ago.
You must say "the pronaa," a
masculine. I'm going to change it today, but I haven't been able to do it yet. So,
who are the children of the Buddhists, of
the Buddhas, but the Bodhisattvas? And what
is the Tibetan one for that? And the "c"
when I tell a man he
is the daughter of the Buddhas means
Bodhisattva. Guess what the
three main paths are. The path that
the Buddhists recommend is Buddhist. The one they
recommend is the desire of the government and the desire to become
enlightened to help billions of
planets. And that is the entry point
for those who want to achieve
enlightenment. What secret part is that
referring to? There is only one left: the
understanding of emptiness. The pen. The
last line is about the pen. If
someone teaches you the pen.
You correctly enter the ocean, you begin to cross it.
The first three main ones are already
hidden in the first verse, so
you can end the class early, but I won't.
As you already know, I'm going to
go to the sweetest points. He talks
about the first line, which is the
essence of all the
Buddhas' teachings, and the way
Pavón Carricoches wants to talk about this in his
commentary is that he wants to talk about what the
Buddhas' teachings are not.
So it's very interesting that on the
same day,
our Lahm, morning or
afternoon, touches on the same point, which is: don't
waste
your mental property, which is so valuable.
Don't infect it with things that will last a
thousand years. Be careful with what you
study. So that's the topic here.
And they have a letter,
a letter from Son Capa that he wrote to
his mother for someone except Words for
100 dollars. Who are Lama Um
following that imam, and Fermín
19,
those Rachita ladies who want 100
dollars?
So the director, the principal, it's not
fair,
yes, which the unemployment was, was a shepherd in
the mountains.  And he was just taking care of
dirty sheep, and people were saying they
met him directly on YouTube.
Then I heard a story where they were
able to talk to him, and he said, "You really
met him directly, you
really have a direct line to Manju Siri?"
And he said, "Yeah, it's like this
dirty old shepherd man." He said, "Yeah, I have a
direct line." He said, "Do you mind if I just
ask him a few things to check
some things out? I think if he killed her,
if I had been the mother, I would have told him, '
Go to hell!'" But the mother
said, "Yeah, yeah, ask him things." So they were able to talk to him. He
asked him all these super
difficult points about emptiness, like
the inversion version of
emptiness, just between
consciousness 7 and consciousness 8.
Then he said, "A map." Every time, he
always gave a perfect answer.
So they were able to talk to him. I used to go to him
to get advice from Manju Siri, and
guess what he did after about a year?
He said, "Move it. You know it's a waste
of time
coming here all the time. Why don't you
teach me how to do that?" And so he did.
And so they say that's why they were able to talk. He
wrote so many things. He had a
direct line with Manju Siri.  And very well, then
people made it my new city
[Music]
and then he wrote a letter or map and
in the letter he said, you know, people
are asking me to teach them all the
time, and I decided to just teach the two
pages of the hunger, two pages of
Atiyah, and that was called the Body Silver
for typical ones on the
path to enlightenment, and then
after ten years he said, very well, now
I am the famous teacher, everyone can
teach me, I have invitations everywhere,
and I realized that the
easiest way to teach is the hunger,
little slams. So this is a cappa
speaking after many years of
teaching, he said, I realized that the
best way to teach students
and help them, and that it has everything in them, is
a little wire and mackay.
So it is the first, the next
part of your class, and even
though it is a small teaching on the
steps on the path, it will cover all the
Buddhist teachings that exist on this
planet,
Omar. And for the best,
I am trying, then he mentions Cuy
Osama, since he is a very famous one, and he also
mentions
Area, the jewel of Area organizations,
Shanghai First  The first topic of the
monastery for 12 years,
Benitez also says that those books
aren't complete, but they don't have all of
Buddhism in them. And if you look at that magical
Amaya Tantra today, it doesn't have the
teachings openly in it,
and the Maitreya book, which we
spent 12 years on, doesn't have the
secret teachings in it, but it does have them. So, he
says, if you think about it, this is superior to
those so far back, and those not so far back. Okay,
who said that? They're never cappa.
[Music]
I'm just covering the paragraphs because
we only have 25 minutes, and then you're going to
sleep with your eyes open. And yes, yes,
and he says, "
That way, and this way is the best.
That way, and this way is the best. It's
the best." And this is very interesting:
if you study the Buddha first,
you can read all the other books of the
Buddha, and it's like a key that opens all
the other books. Study the Buddha, and
first, if there's a number one course, it's
going to help you understand all the other
17 courses of the fundamental series.
So, the rhyme is the key for
us courses.
That means  Going from here to there,
about and from there to here,
and 300,000 books in Tibetan are
packaged in this little print.
You can find them packaged in this.
The Hunger, okay?
This is to say, from here to there. If
you want to study by mana or lower
Michelle, the middle, lower,
higher path, first study the Hunger, and that is
the key to all those doors. And if
you want to go all those ports back,
everything is packaged in this little
problem of 14 verses. And gay, by the way, I'm
going to tell you about my
personal experience.
I memorized the work of the Sang to 75
pages, and something happened to me afterward. You know, I
'm just selling the
idea of ​​memorizing it, and even if it's in
English or Chinese, it didn't matter.
Memorize it in your language, in Spanish, it doesn't matter.
I'm going to tell you something very
good:
memorize it. It's a book that's talking in
your head all day,
okay? Very strange things are going to happen to you. Well,
those are Cappa talking in your head.
You have Maitreya talking in your head
all day.
Little bits, it's like
rock and roll songs, they're going to be living in your
head, and not even  We listened to it until tomorrow and
we were having fun when we were coming
here
little bits of the song called
the three main paths are going to be
coming your mind is arguing
with your girlfriend and suddenly out comes Capa says
the path that pleases the wizards
then he's telling them my
personal experience of this girl from
number one said I experienced it ok and it's
very cool it's fun I think it is and
memorized it's a book by a Buddha it
changes your brain
and brain by the way not to brag it's
becoming more viewed every year I don't know
how long it's going to stop
but there are books that do something to your CV
IQ and it's something very
cool you should try it
and then then you can use it for
your business you're going to be a business person
and a better business person
this will be more capable if you have more man
just you man Trella talking in your
mind all day like a
rock and roll star song and decide 50 and 50
in balance 50% rock and roll from my
head and 50%
Concapa talking in my head that's my
suggestion
[Music]
and he's just selling the  Hunger
then talks about the first lambri men
Tibet who was the light on the path of
order said and then says by the way
here he repeats what you learned this
morning I think this morning who made
the hunger
because it is called the hunger is the interesting test
then traditionally if you are
asked about the source of hunger and the
answer is for the activity the
answer is the perfection of
wisdom because that refers to the
middle side of the lowest it does not refer to the
thousands of pages to the 25 verses to
the 80 verses of the diamond cutter
which are sometimes called the 300 verses of
700 verses each time they make fewer
decisions which is the shortest and what
kind
in their trachea called a and it is just a
word
if you want a cocktail party
memorize ts so that they recognize you go to
the cocktail party see a handsome guy and
tell him memories this shooter
to be very impressed you don't have to
tell him what
and then here is the perfection of
wisdom and says this is the source
of the hunger of the word of America and
they  I'm going to read this perfection and
nothing else, the one that is the path shared
by the victorious, even if they are in the
past, presented in the future. This is the
path that all the Buddhas have traveled,
but the past, present, and future. This is
the angry one. This is a quote from the
perfection of skills, or you focus
someone for 100 dollars without and guard
the emotion.
Three things you can learn to do in
a class once: sleep with your eyes
open,
you can smile, and that's good too. The
second level is nobody
moves your head. The third is I wake
up when you tell them, being
dollars like Warren
Nahuel Benítez.
In what way? The 100-dollar question, I
forget,
and according to here, the question is that
our cowboys with guns are waiting.
I'm ready.
The perfection of wisdom. The fruits
of the perfection of wisdom
truly possess supposedly the
source of hunger. The ancient sutras of the
diamond cutter,
but are they really cancer?
Wow, being very good,
nothing is different.
They continue,
and cancer goes from possessions.
There is a program that is what comes in
hunger. It is not in the perfection of
wisdom. Mainly, what is the
main theme of the others of the  The perfection
of wisdom, for example, the Time Sutra, does
n't speak of emptiness because it
signifies
an obvious object, an obvious theme of the
perfection of wisdom—that is
emptiness. But compassion is
implicit; it's not alone. Teaching
directly with these great
scriptures,
we talk about what the two themes are,
the two levels: what is obvious and what is
hidden.
So compassion is hidden. If
you want to have a debate, you can say that the
perfection of wisdom speaks of the
two streams of compassion and wisdom.  Uria
and you can't lose the argument if he says yes
you can say no he doesn't have
compassion directly studied and if you
say no you can say of course he
has both and it's a perfect profile debate
you're going to win either way
you can use this kind of logic with your
husband your wife
for Pavón who says here that the source
of the word the rhyme is that quote from the
perfection of wisdom of the sutra of
the perfection of wisdom and that's a
very big thing to
answer people about hunger and
well, they say it was invented by
gay people, which then to say that it wasn't
invented by another type
[Music]
then he starts saying that you can't
waste time, what is the dyn
for this,
already the FARC, a flower of glass because it
is beautiful and fragile, don't mess with your
mind, okay?
A verse from the march that one of the
greatest of the lamas looted before
his stage 200 years before being
able to during the time of Genghis Khan,
it's like he's the nephew of Genghis Khan,
Gotham, so it was you too, just so you have
good luck, I'm
trying to steal because  I'm going to do
the human thing, it's like when you buy a horse
or a car and you ask
everyone and you save them money, you ask
everyone, you say, "Today I'm thinking of
buying a car," and you
ask all your friends, "Have you
had a Toyota?" and "What was your
experience?" Nothing, it's not to be forgotten,
actually, my experience was very good,
I always buy Toyotas, okay, but I don't know,
I have a good experience with Honda, and
then you can say, "And what about
a Force or a Chevy?" You
ask people, "Is
the 2019 model better?" 8. "I don't
want to buy a car that won't serve me." It's the
same as if you're going to buy an
apartment, "Is there a coffee shop nearby?"
6. "I live in the neighborhood?" You ask
people, and people who buy a diamond,
many ask me, they call me. I
'm not even in the
diamond business anymore, and people still call me and
tell me that it's a very big thing to buy,
it's vital, and a lot of money, and you can't
tell if it's fake or real. And you tell me,
when people make a big purchase, they're
always asking, "Why are you
here, Panda?" But when people
buy a gun, they don't take just anything, like
a hungry dog.  Indecisiveness, everything they
go on the street, they eat it up
quickly, they say nothing, they're like hungry, linear dogs,
and they say they go to initiations and
tough stuff, and you pay 30 dollars and they give a
tactical initiation that nobody should
be giving unless you pass 18 courses,
and then you just do it, you don't care
if it's going to make you sick,
and if we're very strange people and we're
more worried about our cars than dharma,
and you take any kind of alarm, you go
to yoga class, the teacher says we're going
to meditate about something weird, and you say,
very good, then we don't
discriminate, we don't
ask them if it's a good project or not,
or what he's trying to say
is that you should be more and more demanding in that,
take any bad teaching that
someone wants to give you, that's the same thing we
talked about this morning, maybe you're going to have to,
I was sitting with my friend
last night after he ate the magic
tofu, like
before, and I almost threw up, and half of it, really,
this isn't chocolate, I said, oh, how delicious, in
one bite, I ate a big bite,
and it was, and
now  The chocolate cake told me
sorry and I said you're going back to hell
and don't worry I'll come for you then
here I learned this is talking
about not taking everything and then it
has a quote from 1000 to a quote
Milarepa who is very famous Milarepa to
be a very interesting guy and I think it's
very important to know something Milarepa is
the most famous meditator in Tibet ok
everyone says that all the
traditions say that he was the
most famous meditator in Tibet and Sukkur
Boom his almost 100 thousand songs which is
a bad translation of avoidara because they
are not 100 thousand songs it's just a
collection of songs is one of the
most important pieces of
poetry
in Tibet
gave me the cake
for the good thing about Milarepa
becoming the most famous meditator in Tibet
is that he never started his
meditation series of meditations
in Liniers he was 50 10 years later than
the average life expectancy at that time he was
50 before he started doing his
big retreats so I don't
Don't tell me you're too old to do retreats. Don't
tell me you're too old to start
meditating. In Haiti, you can start.
If you can teach an
old dog all the tricks, it's
always possible to begin. Don't say you
're too old to start meditating, okay?
When Milarepa, the most famous meditator
of all time, was 50, before he
did his work, before he started
writing, like, "So eat, do it
well," and then he says,
and I told you about his poetry yesterday, I think
the normal Tibetan poetry stays so...
can you tell me, can you tell me
what Milarepa is? Because he says "pan,"
so I translated it like this. Very well, here we go. This was
the point. So, are you with the
point?
If you don't visit me at
the councils that were passed
today, you haven't heard of a real tradition, a
real lineage. The place for him puts the
point. The place, about the place, is
like these hip-hop songs.
You want to sit? You can sit in a
cave in the Himalayas and meditate,
but you're wasting your time. You're just
hurting your legs. Who said that?
The best cave meditator.  Of
all history, Weber said no, don't
waste your time. If you don't have a
good tradition, if it's not an
authentic tradition, an authentic scripture, if it's not
a true teaching, don't
waste your time. I was there, there were
the Himalayas, in the caves of
the Himalayas. I am number one of the Himalayan
caves of the Himalayas. So I
still have six minutes and I'm
going to use them.
And well, I'm ready to do the first
homework question. I'm not going to do all of
today's homework,
and well, I'm going to do it at my own pace.
And if you don't have the homework tomorrow and you have to
relax, I'm sorry.
Three breaths.
Try to sell a meditation.
Someone tried to sell you a teaching.
It has to have three qualities, and if it doesn't have them, don't do it. Do
n't put it in your
precious mental property. Don't break the
glass flower, okay? Number one must have been
taught by the Buddha
because that is superior
because he is omniscient. He knows what to
read and make known. When he wrote the book,
very well,
he was reading your mind when he read it. When he
wrote the book, perhaps he knows what you
need. Number two, and this is
Very important, and I'd like to say something
about the Buddhist lineage.
I grew up Christian,
and I studied
my undergraduate degree at Princeton,
primarily Christian studies.
So I studied a lot, and there's
a very strong tradition. I was going to be
a priest; I had already been accepted into
the seminary. Then I went back,
and I never returned, and that's
another story.
In Christianity, in the study of
Christianity, the further back you go, the
better the information. So there's something
very important about Christian studies.
For example, to get started, you have to
learn Greek, Latin, and
Greek at Oxford,
in the town of Oxford.
But to do that, it wasn't with this, it wasn't
the university of today. But the idea
in Christian studies is, the further back you
go, the
purer the information. And I'm going to
tell you something interesting about
Buddhist studies: the closer you
go to Pavón, for example, the
purer it is. It's very
interesting if you really want to
understand Buddhism.
Go further back, from Son Caputa to Pavón,
because
they made it clearer and clearer, easier and
easier to read.
Easy to study,
then I'm going to tell you something and you're going to
be very disappointed
if you try to read "The Perfection of the
Fruit of the Perfection of Wisdom"
and you don't understand it. You can't understand
anything, forget it.
Don't waste your time.
The last thing we're going to translate in this
school, in the other teachings of
Buddha, except for the Diamond Workshop, is if
you translate "The Perfection of
Wisdom" and publish it. Nobody is going to
understand it at all. You don't
need every generation of
explanations. You can't read it. You can't read it.
If you forget what
the Chinese call it, it hasn't even been
taught, and 300 years, as far as I know, you can't
read it. Forget it. You don't need them. They're capable. You do
n't need a
blackout here, and you need six, and there's because it gets clearer and clearer.
Then
you can understand the next generation.
Back then, contrary to the
studies that Christianity said, in
this tradition, the more years you go
back, the
better the presentation gets. With the
years, the translation begins. They're
capable of doing it for 30 years,
but it doesn't go beyond that because otherwise you're
not going to understand anything.  It's
very difficult then in this
tradition.
As the years passed, it became
purer and clearer. That's the second
piece of advice: read the book.
This second piece of advice is about
three books that have gone through the
process of purification for each
generation.
The recent books in the stride for
the mouth law. If there's a suggestion from Leticia, there's the
first one: keep
the things that the Lord doubts are there, but
study the study through a
trading and translate tradition where the
presentation became
more accessible with each generation. And by the
way, the presentation of Chatruc and of
was clear for people in his time
according to Buddhism. People
get stupider with each generation
just because they didn't have cars and
planes. Don't you think that
past generations were stupid? They memorized
all the books while teaching them. We ca
n't do it. See what he
said. They will have kirti. His comments are
clear for their times, and the Buddha's sutras
will be clear for their time. So
this is a recent comment.
That's the second piece of advice. Going
back
through the generations, who
made it increasingly accessible for you,
don't forget the relationship between the  Precise
and accessible
if you're not making Mabel
Tofik chocolate cakes,
make your presentation like a master of it. It's
already accessible, modern, sex, interesting,
toka rock and roll. If you have to
do it
tomorrow, it can't be my
guy who did Made in Taiwan.
You can ask him for basics. I need the video
of the guy who did Made in Taiwan,
and if he has it, we can seal it tomorrow.
The claws that she has it
when it doesn't matter how fun and
accessible it is, but it doesn't corrupt it. Tell us
the four princes of the main
two of the main rules of those
rock and roll matters, and teach us
three. Very good. The last thing,
the third requirement of a teaching is
not to open your teaching to this. It has to
come from the Buddha,
and it has to be passed on in a pure form.
That's the second. And the third, there must be
people who used it and had results
and have success stories. There must be
testimonials. There have to be people, and this
was for two thousand years, and nobody perceives the
emptiness. So maybe we should
cancel it.
Someone who studies so much, when they go,
yogi, not even the diamond people, the diamond angel, did
anyone know her? The answer is
yes,
in our Pavón lineage.  Pavon, Ryan
Grim, car night in range, parents, Concapa,
all these guys knew her
because they studied the 18
practical trending courses.
So that's the third requirement: it has to
work for people, and they
passed it on to the next generation. Those two
parts of the third, okay, you
should see if it has to work for
people. There has to be evidence that it works
for people, and what works
for them, they had to have said
students, for example, your
spiritual partner, Lord Ducati, voice, and he's
more Cappa, had such a knack
for finding their own fence, Jokin, and they
passed it on. It really happened to them; they met her, they saw her, she trained them.
Real stories, stories, there are
real books about their conversations.
So we'll do this kind of thing where it
really worked for someone, it really
worked for someone. So that's your
first homework question, and
unfortunately, you're not going to be able to do
your homework tomorrow,
and I have to write the part about the
four courses we're covering and
the periods. I know how long each
one lasted,
and it's all in your readings, in your hand,
all the information you need. But
the first homework question is for the day after
tomorrow,
and what are the three qualities of  The
number one Buddhist teaching of Lord
number two,
and if it got purer and
clearer,
people cleaned up the things that people
added to it.
If someone asked me to translate
yoga, their work was very difficult, it was very
big. It's clear to me that, like the
fourth chapter, someone else put it in, and there are
many teachings like that. Who isn't a
Buddhist?
And you see its back where people
added things to it. People don't do that.
So, the third one
must have success stories.
That's a good Buddhist book, and we're going to
start tomorrow.
It's multipurpose. We're going to finish
lesson 4. Here's a break. Yesterday I tried
to teach everything slowly, but it's not going to
work, so we're going to
focus on the assignments. You can read
the text; you can read it. This
is probably the longest reading
of all the courses, 6. And there's
because I was lazy. Since I worked everything
for the course, I could only use my old
translation that I already published in the course,
so I didn't have to do anything. But it's
rich. The other courses aren't as
long.
We reached 400 verses written per
area. It goes from  6
They say he was a student of
long Chinese areas,
perhaps he was
[Music],
probably written around 400 AD,
and it describes... Now
we've done the definition of the teacher,
now we're going to do the definition of the
student, the qualities of a
student, and this is traditional in
Buddhism. Before you study Buddhism,
you talk about what a qualified teacher is, qualified,
yes, but what is the teacher? It
says yes, but when is there a
qualified student? So they also have a
list of the qualities of the student. This is
probably the shortest and it
has three parts. There are many other
lists that are very long, but the goal
of the Asia One course is to present
these things to you in ten classes, all of
Buddhism. So we can't say to make
long lists.
The first one is, let's say, the first
quality. You know, "schürrle" (
full)
just means corner and also
means ex, like ex, like ex, taste of bad.
If we're talking about this morning, it
meant an open mind. It means
that you don't take a position. You go to class.
A good Buddhism student
comes to class with an open mind,
and it doesn't mean that they accept everything, not at
all. It means to listen, to listen.
So it means that they go to class and
are open to new ideas. That's
how you get to...  That's the attitude they
have when they arrive in class.
They're open to new ideas.
Maitreya says he does
n't accept them, he doesn't accept them, and then he
asks questions. "Visit," "It fits
with you," "With what you know." There are 3
days, God, God, a light gold.
There are 3 actions and 3 meanings.
9.
What a bad day! And he takes it live and cuts it short. The
last one,
but what does this refer to, these three
tests of new information? Like checking
new information, I don't remember. We had it
in spirit, I
know who,
since it has a conflict with something the
teacher said before, and the teacher said on
Friday, don't eat meat, and then on Saturday,
and you eat meat, so you don't pass the
third test,
which is your own experience. If I notice
that when I eat meat I feel bad and
my cholesterol doesn't go up, there must be something
wrong that gives bad karma. And what is the
second one to cut
the logic? Use logic, it makes sense, it makes sense, it's
logical. So those
are the three tests. The student is one who
arrives in the classroom with an open mind,
and from Turkey, yes, check singers, which is
part of the second quality of the
student, where lumen
means ready, that has a
high IQ, but what kind of  An
efficient team, intellectually and spiritually, with a spiritual
IQ.
When I started the courses,
26 years old, in New York, this first course, I
think, we had five or six people,
and I was giving the assignments. It was the
first time anyone had given assignments for
a Buddhist class. I noticed there are two types
of people. One type always gets 100
on their assignments. They are
the least friendly in the class. They are
very smart, and if you say the teacher, yes,
the best teacher, has the best
grades, they would be, but they are
irritating and not good to us or
the other students. And there are
people who had 90-89,
number one on the assignments, but they were number one in
treating others well. What is a
teacher? I was saying that in Haiti, I
think those two different types of
IQ are two different types of IQ.
In America, we learn to take many
tests. I was number one in Arizona.
My grades were the highest
analyzed in my year, and I went to meet the
president of all.
So there is one type of intelligence
for taking tests, but it doesn't
mean you have
emotional intelligence or kindness. This is a
different type of IQ.
So here we are talking about the
second type of IQ.
spiritually more with a
higher spiritual IQ.
In fact, in Miami, the capital,
there's a very, very old test where you
feel intellectually
spiritual,
although in some way,
then they
say they start crying in class
sometimes. Put water says that it starts
talking
and they start talking about the city.
It's like listening to your favorite song,
they start crying if you have one,
but don't try to cry in class.
[Laughter] I'll
leave it at that. That's why they
put onions in the middle,
enchiladas from their pack, and the sky, the
night.
The third quality of the
fake Beijing weed student
has a big vision, and I'm talking
about other planets. Of those kinds of
people who I've seen go out and drink a
lot and stand up. A liquid seems like a
while. They can look at their phone afterward, but
there's a world out there. It has stars that
are no more than two inches where
most people live. Go and see
the stars
in an acap and drink, in a way that
jumps across the sky. In
my instinct, it means think big.
This, this training of Asian teachers,
we're teaching, we're talking about
protecting them, we're talking about food, and
we have a feeling that if this  It's going well, it's
spreading quickly to
many places, it's just that we've never
organized it before. Now we'll be
trying to organize it. So, having
this kind of water vision means
you have a big vision in your mind and
you want to help every person on this
planet.
And again, it doesn't mean that every person
becomes a Tibetan Buddhist. It doesn't mean that. It
means that people
start using the four steps, people
start using these ideas that you can
convert to become successful by
sharing and giving to others.
And we think it's to give back to the
world's culture, that people
forget who started it. That's my goal. I
want them to love it and for the world's culture to
change. I want to change the culture of
other planets, and I want everyone to
forget who started it. Okay, Louis
Tardes, Sidewalk, who started it?
People, public libraries,
who started it? Benjamin
Franklin, and a lot of people don't know that.
Before, you had to be very rich to have a
book because they had to be
handwritten, and only rich people had them.  Books,
if we don't let others read them,
then he said let's have all the
rich people put their books in a
building so people can
read them. And now, less so in this country,
probably all over the country there are
public libraries, you can go and check out the books, and they
forgot who started it, so that's
the goal,
we want the spiritual Benjamin Franklins,
where
his picture is even on the $100 bill,
that proves he's cool.
[Music]